# Amandeep Singh (1) Featured

Seeking roles in Software Development Fullstack/Backend Engineer. Having 2+ years of experience in product organisation, proficient in

JAVA, SQL, HTML, Javascript, XML, CQL, Spring, Spring Boot, Microservices, JPA, MVC, Hibernate, JSP, Web services, REST



Current Designation: Associate Software Engineer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Current Company: Publicis Sapient Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Mechanical]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Development, JAVA, SQL, HTML, Javascript, XML, CQL, Hibernate, jQuery, JSP, AJAX, Spring Boot, Spring

Mvc,Struts,Microservices,Core Java,JDBC,Postgresql,MySQL,Cassandra,Message Queue,Apache

Tomcat, Banking, Kanban, Kibana, Splunk, Rest, SOAP, Web Services

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### Summary

Working as an Associate Technology L1 at Publicis Sapient in Bangalore.

Having 2+ years of experience in JAVA, J2EE and Frameworks like Struts, Spring, Hibernate and Web services for Web application development, support and maintenance.

Having 2+ years of experience in Banking domain and payment gateways as well as integration of different payment mode and channels.

Good understanding of various phases of Software Development life Cycle (SDLC) like Requirement Analysis, Planning, Design, Development, Testing and Deployment.

Good Experience of Object Oriented Programming, Multithreading concepts and Collections. Good knowledge in Exception Handling, writing Custom Exceptions.

Experience in developing applications using Web-Technology, Servlets as well as client-side validation using Javascript and ¡Query. Exposure towards DC/Dr drills and application deployment in Linux and cloud server.

# Work Experience

Publicis Sapient as Associate Software Engineer Sep 2020 to Till Date

Working for a Retail based US client JC Penney.

Integra Micro Systems Pvt Ltd. as Senior Software Engineer

May 2018 to Sep 2020

PROJECT-1:

ORGANIZATION: Integra Micro Systems Pvt LTD. PRODUCT NAME: BBPS (Bharat Bill Payment System)

CLIENT: UCO Bank and Corporation Bank

**ROLE**: Team member

TEAM SIZE: 4

DURATION: March 2019 - September 2020.

TECHNOLOGIES: Java, Multithreading, RESTful API, SOAP, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JSON, XML,

JSP, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, MySQL DB, REDIS, Maven, Eclipse, Apache

DESCRIPTION: Bharat Bill Payment System (BBPS) is an integrated billpayment system in India offering interoperable and accessible billpayment service to customers through a network of agents of registered member as AgentInstitutions(AI), enabling multiple payment modes, and providing instant confirmation of payment. National Payments Corporation of India(NPCI) functions as the authorised Bharat Bill Payment Central Unit (BBPCU), which will be responsible for setting business standards, rules and procedures for technical and business requirements for all the participants.NPCI,as the BBPCU,will also undertake clearing and settlement activities related to transactions routed through BBPS. Existing bill aggregators and banks are envisaged to work as Operating Units to provide an interoperable bill payment system irrespective of which unit has on-boarded a particular biller. Payments may be made through the BBPS using cash, transfer cheques, and electronic modes.

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:**

Tomcat 7 and SVN for repository.

Involved in Client interaction on regular basis to understand the Business of the Client.

Involved in developing business objects layer, business logic layer and Data Access layer using Java, Spring MVC and Hibernate framework.

Involved in developing API's using web services (RESTful and SOAP).

Involved in developing front end using JSP, Jquery, HTML and Javascript.

Data Tables for UI Table with Search, Sort, Pagination options used to display the list.

HSM integration for digital signing and verification of Request/Response XML.

Development and Integration of billers using Reflection API in Java.

Involved in session management using in-memory database REDIS.

Involved in preparing Web services documents and Integration document for different Channels.

Deployment of application in UAT and Production Linux servers.

Involved on Production fixes and Production Support.

Involved in performing Sandbox and UAT certification testing with NPCI and bug fixing.

#### PROJECT-2:

ORGANIZATION: Integra Micro Systems Pvt LTD.

PRODUCT NAME: iASK (Integra's Aadhaar Seeding and KYC framework)

CLIENT: 19 PSU Nationalized Bank's.

ROLE: Team member

TEAM SIZE: 4

DURATION: June 2018 - March 2019

TECHNOLOGIES: Java, JSP, JSON, XML, Struts, JDBC, PostgreSQL, iReport, Tomcat 7 and SVN for

repository.

DESCRIPTION: iASK is a product basically which serves as an AUA server to any AUA/KUA

(Authentication User Agency/KYC User Agency) used by Banks and Telecom organization to authenticate or to get the Aadhaar KYC of the customer from UIDAI. UIDAI doesn't allow direct access to their server. Instead they give license to some agenices which communicates with aadhaar server (CIDR). So if any AUA wants to communicate with aadhaar server has to go via an ASA. NPCI acts as an ASA which connects the AUA's and UIDAI.

### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:**

Involved in Client interaction on regular basis to understand the Business of the Client.

Involved in developing business objects layer, business logic layer and Data Access layer using Java, Struts MVC and JDBC.

Involved in developing API's using web services (RESTful).

Integration of applets with Web application to capture Finger print and Iris.

HSM integration for encryption of data, digital signing and verification of Request/Response XML.

Development of plugins for syncing the KYC data at CBS as per the ISO spec of Bank at CBS (Core Banking System)

Development of utility applications which are responsible for data movement within the system.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Mechanical) from Government College of Engineering Kalahandi, Bhawanipatna in 2016

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Java, SQL	
HTML, JavaScript	

XML, CQL	laukii.com/preview/primitvesume:uname=+5009a5+50500+5a0te0ub5b2+u97tbu5
Spring, Struts, Spring Boot	
Hibernate, jQuery, Spring MVC	
STRUTS MVC	
REST Web Services, SOAP	
Servlets, JSP, AJAX, XHR	
JSON, JDBC, Microservices, Ka	afka
MySQL, PostgreSQL, Cassand	ra
Apache Tomcat, JBOSS, Weblo	ogic
SQLyog, PGAdmin	
SQL Developer, Maven	
Apache Jmeter, Sonarqube	
SVN, iReport, Docker	

# Languages Known

Eclipse, Windows and Linux

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Oriya				
Punjabi				

## **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time